Hello, I'm Pastor Johnny. 希望你在家裡有平安,和神保守你。
Hope you're staying safe at home. 希望你在家裡保持安全。
Today we're going to talk about "You are adopted". 你是被接受的。
You are adopted as God's child. 你是被接受為神的孩子。
神領養你,做他的孩子。
在這個世界,Orphanism 是一個很大的問題。
有一個stat在2015就說,There are 15.1 million children that are orphans. 有一個stat在2015就說,有15.1萬名小孩是被接受的。
Orphanism is a big problem. 孤僻是一個很大的問題。
15.1 million 是好像Russia那麼大,一個國家那麼大。
And fatherlessness, fatherlessness, 在這裡有一個quote,
Never have so many children grown up without knowing what it means to have a father. 從小到大都沒有知道什麼是有一個父親的意思。
Fatherlessness is the most harmful demographic trend of this generation. 父親性是這個世代最嚴重的民族流行。
It is the leading cause of declining child and adult well-being in our society. 這是我們社會中的最大原因,是孩子和成長的原因。
It is also the engine driving our most urgent social problem. 也是我們社會最緊急的社會問題的引擎。
If this trend continues, fatherlessness is likely to change the shape of our society. 如果這個流行繼續下去,父親性將會改變社會的形狀。
This is a family researcher from the United States, David Blankenhorn. 這是一位美國的家庭研究員,David Blankenhorn。
In the time of Paul, child immorality was a big problem. 在布羅時代,聖經時期,孩子的不道德是一個很大的問題。
Maybe the child was disabled. 可能孩子是失去能力了。
Maybe the child was a girl. 可能孩子是一個女孩。
Sometimes, the family might have to abandon the child. 有時候,孩子的家庭就可能被丟棄了。
In the city of Ephesus, when Paul wrote a letter to Ephesus, 在那裡的城市,布羅寫了一封信給那裡的城市人。
There was a problem in the city, called "Death by Exposure". 在那裡的城市,有一個問題叫"死亡被爆炸"。
If the family didn't want the child, 如果那些家庭不想要孩子,
they could have this Roman rule, called "Death by Exposure". 他們可以有這個羅曼法,叫"死亡被爆炸"。
Just like that, they threw the child into a garbage area. 就這樣把孩子丟到垃圾的地方。
If the sun and heat exposed the child, 如果太陽和熱能曝光了孩子,
he would die. 他就會死。
At that time, Paul told them, 當時,布羅對他們說,
"You are adopted as his child." 你是他的孩子。
In Ephesians chapter 1, he said, 在一書一書,他說,
"For he has chosen us before him, 因為他選擇了我們在他面前,
before the creation of the world, 在世界的創造前,
to be holy and blameless in his sight. 以他的眼中,無罪無罪地存在。
In love, he predestined us for adoption 愛,他將我們預定
to sonship through Jesus Christ, 子女遷生到基督基督,
in accordance with his pleasure and will." 以他的喜好和願望。
"神係領養你"。
那時,那些基督徒是怎樣? 那時,那些基督徒是怎樣?
看到那麼多不同的孩子, 看到那麼多不同的孩子,
就這樣被羅曼丟了, right? 就這樣被羅曼丟了,對嗎?
因為可能disabled了, 因為可能不適合了,
可能是女孩子,可能是不適合, 因為有小朋友是要錢的,對嗎?
如果你要錢,可能take away from your social status, 如果你要錢,可能要脫離你的社會的地位,
就不要了他。 那些基督徒在那個city,
叫做Ethesis,那又怎樣呢? 叫做Ethesis,那又怎樣呢?
他看到那些孩子被人abandon了, 他就adopt了他們。
adoption是一個很amazing thing, 是兩個parents,
一個爸爸,一個媽媽, loving family,
adopted an unwanted child, abandoned child,
這個picture is a picture of what God has done for us.
今天我們會看神領養我們, 有三個aspects,
第一,我們有一個新的家庭, new family,
第二,是一個新的identity, 第三,是一個新的inheritance,
第一,我們為甚麼會有一個新的家庭呢?
第一,是因為是天父initiate,
God initiated it through Jesus Christ,
今天我們會讀Galatians 4:4-5
及至時候滿足, 神就差遣他的兒子為女子所生,
且生在律法意下, 要把律法意下的人屬出來,
叫我們得著兒子的名分。
在這裡寫, 神把他的兒子生下為女子,
以律法下的兒子, 讓我們可以得著兒子的名分。
神把我們的兒子領養為他的孩子,
第二,我們會看到, 我們的新的family,
是through Jesus Christ,
God sent his son, 他差遣主耶穌幫我們,
去救我們,
還有我們看到, 我們的新的family,
是我們united with brothers and sisters,
這個家庭是有不同的brothers and sisters,
我們基督徒的brothers and sisters,
brothers in Christ,
第一,我們有一個新的家庭,
第二,我們有一個新的identity,
之前我們rejected,
we were rejected because of sin,
我們有罪,
有罪我們和神的關係分裂了,
that now we are reborn, redeemed,
and remade a child in Christ,
之前我們被罪control我們,
we were slaves to sin,
但現在我們有freedom,
freedom to serve God,
去侍奉神,
serve God and serve righteousness,
we are now free to be righteous,
在John 1是這樣說,
凡接待他的,就是信他名的人,
他就賜他們權並作神的兒女,
這等人不是從血氣生的,
不是從情慾生的,
也不是從仁義生的,
乃是從神生的。
For those who received him,
those who believed in his name,
he gave the right to become children of God,
children of God,
如果你相信主耶穌,
接受了他,
是你的頭子,
你可以做他的孩子,
you are his child.
第三,我們有一個new inheritance,
new inheritance,
在Romans 8說,
因為凡被神的靈引導的,
都是神的兒子,
我們所受的,
不是奴僕的心,
仍舊害怕,
所受的,
乃是兒子的心,
因此我們呼叫阿爸父,
聖靈與我們的心,
同證我們是神的兒女,
既是兒女,
便是後子,
就是神的後子,
與基督同作後子,
如果我們和他一同受苦,
也必和他一同得榮耀。
你所受的靈,
並不使你成為奴僕,
讓你活在恐懼中,
讓你再次生活在恐懼中,
但是你所受的靈,
帶給你兒子的育成,
而我們呼叫阿爸父,
靈自身與我們的靈,
證明我們是神的兒女,
現在如果我們是兒女,
我們就是後子,
是神的後子,
與基督同作後子,
如果我們一同受苦,
也必和他一同得榮耀。
我們是後子,
與基督同作後子,
我們與主耶穌,
一同得榮耀,
這個榮耀是什麼呢?
一個新的天堂,
一個新的地球,
主耶穌復活,
我們有一天也會有,
一個復活的身體,
我們也會復活,
我們一同得榮耀,
與天堂的寬廣,
我們與主耶穌,
一同分享天堂的未來。
哇!
我們說了三件事,
神領養我們,
有三件新事物,
一個新的家庭,
新的家庭,
一個新的身份,
新身份,
還有第三件事,
新身份。
保羅在他的書,
《二法所書》,
說我們是他的孩子,
問題就是,
我們是否在演戲,
像他的孩子,
像他的兒女,
不是,
如果我們是他的孩子,
我們會奉服神,
我們會改變生命,
我們會模仿耶穌,
我們會變得像耶穌,
在第五章,
保羅叫那些"Ephesians",
做什麼?
"The imitators of God",
"The imitators",
因為你是他的孩子,
你要怎樣?
要模仿神,
好像神一樣,
是不是?
第二樣,
他說"Walk in love",
"Walk in love",
你要走在愛的方面,
你也要模仿神的愛,
還有什麼?
他說"Walk not as unwise, but as wise",
因為你是他的孩子,
你要聰明,
要聰明,
"Do not be drunk on wine,
which leads to debauchery,
but be filled with the Spirit",
給聖靈充滿,
你做他的孩子,
你沒有給神的聖靈充滿,
"Be filled with the Spirit of God",
我們在華人的文化,
是很不同的,
和西方文化,
是不是?
這個亞洲文化,
華人的文化,
是很表演性的,
是不是?
我知道你們讀書有很多壓力,
很表演性的,
爸爸媽媽說,
為什麼你只有90%,
為什麼不是100%呢?
是不是?
所以令到我們好像要很緊張,
我們的性,
我們的表演性,
我們時時都要保護面子,
給面子,
Hide all your weaknesses,
So that people don't look down on you,
Hide your failures,
在這個華人的社會,
是有時很難的,
是不是?
是有很多壓力的,
我們做基督徒,
有時我們transfer,
我們的Chinese culture,
into our faith as well,
有時我覺得自己要做很多很多的事,
去侍奉神,
然後神才會愛我,
才會領養我做祂的孩子,
一個problem with faith and works,
你是不是好像這樣,
經常做事,
希望別人去impress,
be impressed by you,
有時我做牧師,
都會有這樣的struggle,
是不是?
如果我傳福音,
傳到很多人,
那神就可能很開心,
會love me more,
But that's not true,
There's nothing that I can do,
that would make God love me more or less,
God loves me,
and His love is consistent,
and my identity needs to be found in Him,
as His child, as His son,
我們如果接受了,
神是愛我們,
神是領養我們,
是祂的孩子,
那我們不用perform,
我們不用去教會,
因為我們希望神開心,
可以讓我們去天堂,
不是的,
我們去教會,
不是去pleased,
Hopefully God will be pleased with us,
我們回教會,
因為我們是worshippers,
We are worshippers of God,
We don't come to church to please God,
and hopefully He will save us,
hopefully He will let us into heaven,
No, we are adopted as His child,
我們是祂的孩子,
我們回來教會,
是去敬拜,
因為we are worshippers,
we are worshippers,
神adopted我們,
給我們有個freedom,
去serve 祂,
We serve Him not because of obligation,
我們為甚麼去serve呢?
We serve because we love Him,
這是很不同的difference,
big difference,
Being versus doing,
神愛我們,
我們可以愛身邊的人,
Not because we need to get love from each one of them,
We are not desperate for love,
from relationships,
from society,
We are free to love,
because God's love is in and through,
love goes in and through us,
goes in and through us,
另一個林宣豪,
Jeremy Lin,
他剛剛上年贏過NBA Championship,
in 2019,
The first Asian to win an NBA Championship,
但你知不知道他打了多久的時間?
How long did he play for in the finals?
He played for only maybe a minute or two minutes,
在game over那次,
差不多over那次,
他要有人sub,
他就come in,
He only played for a minute or two,
他自己懷疑自己,
Am I really a champion?
我只是打了一兩個分鐘,
在那個final那次,
做NBA的球員,
不容易的,
你的stat,
你射得好,
如果你的stat好,
你defend得好,
You get to play,
但你一射得不好,
或者coach覺得你不是team的system,
他就可能put you on the bench,
You can't play,
但林雪玉怎樣說,
他的identity不是一些stat,
不是射得多好,
多準,
His identity is found in God,
in God's love for him,
and he is a champion,
not because of what he's done,
the minute that he played,
but because of what God has done,
in and through his life,
He is a champion,
and we are champions,
we are adopted as his child,
not because of what we've done,
不是因為我們做了什麼special,
我們自己不是可以當我們自己,
It's because of what God has done,
through Jesus Christ,
You are adopted.
我記得我們有一個學生,
他之前,
小時候,
他爸爸媽媽經常和他讀聖經,
讀什麼呢?
讀The Book of Judges,
or The Book of Deuteronomy,
經常說,
如果你不做這件事,
神會punish你,
他長大的時候,
就經常覺得神是一個punishing God,
他經常覺得他自己是錯的,
He's not good enough,
He's not good enough to be accepted,
as his son and daughter,
to be adopted,
to be loved,
他覺得他自己不是神愛,
我記得我和他hiking一次,
on the top of the mountain,
or the hill 那個時候,
他就和我說,
Johnny, 我很嬲神,
I told God to strike me down,
他覺得神很,
so against him,
我就說, 你冷靜點,
神愛你的,
我們開始讀新約的時候,
其實他沒有讀新約,
其實舊約,新約都說,
God loves us,
God is slow to anger,
quick to listen,
and abundant in love,
in the Old Testament,
他慢慢看新約的時候,
他發現神猜不住耶穌,
因為祂為我們,
為我們死,
主耶穌為我們死,
釘十字架,
and He is a love child,
and now,
He is willing to go out in love,
to reach other people,
other groups,
non-Christians,
and so today,
I hope that you know,
you are adopted as a child of God,
there's nothing you can do,
that will change that,
that God loves you,
我們有三個application,
第一樣,
是你,
do you realize,
你是一個child of God,
神是領養你的,
我希望如果你未,
你是可以接受主耶穌是你的救主,
and you have confessed Jesus to be the Lord and Savior in your life,
你會有一個new identity,
a new family,
and a new inheritance in Jesus Christ,
第二樣,
are you acting like a child of God,
a son and a daughter,
are you acting like a son or a daughter,
沒有的話,
we need to be imitators of God,
be more and more like Jesus Christ,
walk in the light,
walk in His love,
be filled with the spirit,
被聖的寵物,
我們是不是acting like children of God,
第三樣,
if we are acting like children of God,
are we sharing His love,
我們在這個society,
在這個時間,
這麼多的hopelessness,
are we being the light of Christ,
are we going out in the love of Christ,
to love others,
to give people hope in this dark time,
the greatest hope is the living hope,
and that is Jesus Christ,
there is no greater time now,
to share the love of God,
to share the hope of Christ,
and so I hope that today,
you know you are an adopted child of God,
and that God wants to live in and through you,
to be the light in this city,
in this dark time,
God bless you.